Diego Favero - Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

Lençois - BA - Brazil, 46960-000 | +55 75 998123412 diego.g.favero@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/faverodiego/ | https://orisha1.gitlab.io/my_site/

SKILLS

- **Expert in:** PHP, OOP, MySQL, JavaScript, Laravel, Microservices, API's.
- Intermediate in: TypeScript, React, Vue, TDD, AWS, Docker, MongoDB.
- Basic in: Kotlin, Node JS, Python, GoLang.
 Used to: CI/CD, Jira/Trello, Scrum/KanBan, Linters, Design Patterns, Clean Code.
- Want To Learn/Improve: Machine Learning, GoLang, DevOps, Python, R.

Experience Summary

I have been using **PHP** and its 'sidekicks' such as Javascript and SQL for web development since **1999** when I started to be an intern in the university's computer's lab. (Yes, at that time, JS and SQL were still sidekicks to PHP). I surfed many waves during this time: Monolith, MVC, Frameworks, Microservices, Servless. Now, I am preparing for the AI wave.

Today I consider myself a better fit as a **backend developer** than frontend although, I am able to work in any stage from a system development:

Since analyzing system requirements, going through server setup, database design and administration, team managing, coding (Structure, Backend and Frontend), test and deployment!

I am really up to start to learn new technologies.

- Currently, I have based my personal and professional projects on microservices architecture, containerized using Docker.
- Golang and PHP (Symfony or Laravel) as BackEnd.
- Javascript (Vue or React) as FrontEnd.
- Kotlin for mobile
- MySql and MongoDB for data storage.

I Have a good knowledge about Photography, Video Editing and Audio Production, able to use many software such as Adobe suite, Logic Pro, Ableton Live and many others.

I have been DJing since 2007.

In my free time I like outdoor sports such as rock climbing, trekking and mountain biking, and sometimes, I make awesome woodwork ! (Most of my house's furniture is made by me) .

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Science - Information Systems, (B.A.Sc.) Feb 1999 - Dec 2003 São Paulo State University Júlio de Mesquita Filho, Bauru - SP.

The Course, basically, is a shortened form of Science Computers plus company management course. In short words: It teaches how to apply computer based systems for companies.

The São Paulo State University (aka UNESP) is in the top 4 Brazilian Rankings and it is in the top 400 worldwide.

The Information Systems Bachelor at UNESP is the **first** course of its kind in Brazil. And since them it has been always ranked as #1 in Brazil.

EXPERIENCE

Sr FullStack Software Engineer - Feb 2022 - Sep 2022

AutoSnap, Remote, Independent contractor through Buink

Stack: PHP (Laravel), MySql, MongoDB, Jquery, Javascript and TypeScript, Vue, MicroServices, Docker, Sentry.

Using Laravel Batches and Job's the Backend was able to process massive amounts of data asynchronously without affecting page's performance. It is about vehicle lists. Each seller uploads a file containing many car information, including images. The backend then:

- Store all the info.
- Process the images (resize, sign, etc) and using Google's Machine Learning models, identify the image according to a car feature.
- Eg: If an image is from a steering wheel, an icon from electric assistance will be placed over the image.
 - Export the information according to different marketplace requirements.
 - Monitoring Production Errors (Sentry).

Also, there is a notification schema, using Laravel's Events and Laravel Echo Server: Due to its asynchronous architecture the notification container was in charge to channel messages from backend to frontend anytime. As so, the user could be warned when a heavy job has been processed, with error of full success.

Sr FullStack Software Engineer June 2020 - Jan 2022

Alooba, Remote

It is a startup company from Australia which recently got a substantial investment. It provides solutions for hiring processes focused on Data Sciences roles.

Tech Stack: Laravel (Lumen), Microservices, Docker, PostgreSQL, Event Driven, Test (phpUnit & Jest), React (functional), TypeScript, SonarQube.

My daily tasks:

- Quickly fix bugs (Mostly from monolithic AKA "old app").
- Migration : The "old app" has been migrated to a microservice architecture.
- Add new features. As the migration evolves, new features have been added to the services.
- Code Review & Testing on tasks done by other developers.
- Monitoring Production Errors (OpsGenies).

Sr FullStack Software Engineer Aug 2014 - June 2020

One Man Army, Remote

My role here was basically everything: Project, design, architecture, frontend, backend, devops, dba, marketing, selling, legal concerns, new features, etc.

The idea was to have a management system generic enough to attend any demand and specific enough to actually solve the demand.

Using the concepts of product, service and sectors, the system is able to calculate all the costs considering all the steps on a production lifecycle. With a few modifications (mostly about labels), the very same system was used to manage. _ Dried fruit production. From soil preparation until the final product.

TechStack: PHP (symphony), GoLang, MongoDB, MySQL, Kotlin, Docker, Microservices.

- Warehouse from a big electronic music festival.
- Hostel. Managed the available and allotted beds and reservations
- Bar. Could manage the daily accounts and liquor stock.

The last version got lots of new features in order to manage music festivals.

- Ticket generation and online selling.
- Check in on site.
- NFC cards, credits, top up, spending (for internal consumption).
- Real time Accounting.

Mid PHP Developer Nov 2012 - Jul 2014

NetSar, Remote

Tech Stack: PHP (symphony), MySql, Javascript (jquery), Monolith, API's (SOAP/REST servers).

It is a medium software company in Brazil providing solutions for travel shop's. It was a home based job. I was leading a small team (me plus 2 programmers, occasionally a designer) responsible for re-write the old scripts into a new Symfony based platform. Eventually, I did write codes for new features . Most of the system was based on SOAP/REST servers!

Reason for getting off: In May 2014 I had a motorcycle crash, which cost me three broken ribs, a pierced lung, a week in the hospital and almost my life. After that I decided to give myself some time so I asked to get off for travel.

Jr PHP Developer Jan 2010 - Nov 2012

Ecentry, Florianopolis, SC, Brazil

I Was working on a Fidelity Program System owned by Lufthansa Flight Company. This system is responsible for managing the Fidelity Points Program for the ones who sell Lufthansa tickets. It was a huge system within almost 2M users, translated into more than 80 languages.

Tech Stack: PHP, MySql, Javascript (ExtJs), Monolith

I had two main functions:

- 1 Maintenance: Had to quickly fix any reported bug.
- 2 New Interface and Database Optimization: While no bugs were reported, I had a mission to check and optimize the SQL's query and system performance. To do so, I was migrating all queries to be executed by Python Scripts.

The new interface was developed using ExtJS Framework.

Reason to get off: I was sick of having to spend two hours every day in the Brazilian traffic. After being denied work home based, I asked to quit.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (pt-BR): native speaker.

English: Advanced/Professional proficiency.

I (really) learned English when was **living** in Amsterdam (2008-2009), today I could say that I am aware of my strong Brazilian accent, also a few mess when need to use 'in', 'on', 'at', etc, although, I think I can **express** myself clearly enough to hold any kind of conversation, written or **spoken**.

Spanish: Intermediary.

Due to its **similarity** to Portuguese, I can understand Spanish very well when spoken and fully when read . But I can not speak as good as I speak English

French/Italian: Self Learning.

Like Spanish, these other **latin** languages are kind of easy to understand, but I still don't get much of it when spoken. I just need a bit more practice.

TECHNICAL SKILLS (out of 10 levels)

Level 8 (I would be able to perform a workshop of these right now)

PHP OOP Mysql

Level 7 (I can work very well using these, with some kind of expertise)

Javascript Jquery Symfony

Laravel MicroServices Linux (web server setup)

Level 6 (I Can do it! Maybe I'll use google to check any syntax or a forgotten detail)

GoLang API TypeScript

React Vue .js Design Patterns

SASS/LESS Git AWS
SOAP/REST CI/CD DBA
Kotlin Docker TDD
React Nginx BDD
NoSql MongoDB Node.js

Level 5 (I can do it! I have already used it! Just give a few days on google)

XML Python SqlServer Angular TSql PL/Sql

Level 4 (tools I already used, but not that much, so I am able to use it)

ExtJS Kendo UI Codelgniter

Level 3 (I know what is and how to apply, but never worked using those before)

Ruby Kubernetes WordPress

Bootstrap Pearl

Level 2 (Languages I learned in college, but never used professionally)

C, C++ Java Pascal Cobol Lua Delphi Assemble Fortran ASP

SOFT SKILLS

Mentorship/CollaborationCritical ThinkingProactiveEffective CommunicationProblem SolvingDiversity

Ethic Creativity

MY GOALS

MultiTask and	vast	tech	knowl	edge:	l can f	it in	many	position	ons in	i the IT	depart	ment.

_ Can travel anytime.

_ Dare me for new challenges!

_ I think 'out of the **box'** and love to learn.

_ I can inject new market vision ('cause I live the **Brazilian** reality, would be nice info and **experiences** exchange about this huge and growing market we have around here).

Interests

Augmented Reality UI / UX New Technologies

Qubits Data Security Networks

Big Data Machine Learning Al

INTERESTS beyond IT

A few things I like to do and learn about in my spare time :

Photo / Video / Audio Production and Edition
_ Sports -> Climbing, Mountain bike, Surf, SlackLine and Trekking.
_ Healthier life and food .
_ Travel
_ Quantum physics.
_ Yoga and Capoeira .
Politics and Economy .
_ Dogs .
_ Simple Life .
Carpenter and Architecture .

Why hire me?

Because I have a full **domain** knowledge of how to attend to the job needs (if it is in my **skills set**, otherwise, I am fully open to learning it) with a few pluses acquired by life experience. And, I have a passion for working with **technologies**!

Want to see more?

Please, ask for a code samples or visit :

https://orisha1.gitlab.io/my_site/ https://github.com/orisha